DANEEN MAYS

Rahway, NJ 07065 | 732-306-2058 | Mays.d87@Gmail.com

Professional Summary

Experienced Quality Assurance Engineer & Junior Software Developer with expertise in software development and testing strategies. Collaborates effectively with developers to identify and resolve issues pre-release. Possesses exceptional organizational and multitasking skills, delivering exceptional results while boosting company morale.

Skills

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
- Currently Learning: Java
- Databases: PostgresSQL

- Frameworks: React, Express
 Technologies and Libraries: Node.js, Redux, Command
 Line, APIs, Version Control (Git), axios, cors, sass,
 CSS: Bootstrap, Flexbox,
- Appium, WebdriveriO, Selenium-Webdriver

Employment History

Quality Assurance Engineer

Jul 2019 - Current

Ellevest

- Applied Agile methodologies to progressive and regressive testing through iterative software development, managing releases to ensure timely and high-quality product delivery.
- Developed and optimized test plans for manual and automated software testing in JavaScript.
- Experienced in various types of testing, including unit, integration, performance, acceptance, regression, E2E, API and A/B testing, on both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Monitored bug resolution, maintained/created and fixed automated tests to ensure optimal product performance and maintained documentation.
- Collaborated with developers to tackle ongoing problems and provided performance improvements from QA perspective.
- Utilized technical tools, including Postman, JIRA, Circle Ci, GitHub, VS code, Confluence, and Zoom.

Lead Quality Assurance Engineer

Oct 2016 - Jun 2019

Oracle, Inc New York, NY

- Led outsourced testing team, providing guidance on testing methods, conducting meetings, and defining project goals.
- Conducted detailed tests to measure tracking and viewability metrics on various devices. Produced test case scenarios, validated and communicated bugs to developers, and implemented solutions to improve product quality.
- Utilized technical tools, including MySQL, Linux Terminal, Charles Debugging Web Proxy tool, JIRA software tracking tool, Dev tools, GitHub, Cross-Browsing Testing, Virtual Box, MS Excel, and MS OneDrive.

Junior Data Analyst May 2015 - Oct 2016

S&P Global Market Intelligence

- - Utilized technical tools and software, including Microsoft Excel & Outlook, SFDC, RDR, and CORE software.
- Analyzed data using Pivot Tables, VLOOKUPS, and other formulas in Excel to provide fast and accurate insights. Met deadlines and project requirements by recording missing data points.

• Participated in internal audits to ensure compliance with quality management system standards.

Coding Projects

Bloom | Github: https://github.com/PlantApp:

• As a Junior Software Engineer, my responsibilities included developing front-end and back-end features, optimizing app performance, and collaborating with the team to ensure timely and high-quality project delivery.

Squawkers | Github: https://github.com/ojichon/SQUAWKERS.git

• As a Junior Software Engineer, my responsibilities included developing front-end and back-end features, troubleshooting issues, and working with the team to maintain the app's functionality and performance.

Education

Full-Stack Software Development Program

Apr 2023 Remote

DigitalCrafts

Remote

Bachelor of Science: Mathematics

May 2017

The College of New Rochelle

New York

GPA: 3.6

URL

LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/daneen-mays | GitHub: https://github.com/DaneenM | Portfolio: https://daneenm.github.io/My-Portfolio/